export const questions = [
  {
    question: "Why is it not ethically sufficient for multinational corporations to simply follow the laws of the countries in which they do business?",
    options: [
      "Unethical practices may be legal in other countries.",
      "Corporations are bound by the laws of their home country.",
      "Some of the laws in foreign nations may be unenforceable.",
      "Laws in other countries may unduly restrict business."
    ],
    correctOption: "Unethical practices may be legal in other countries.",
    difficulty: "beginner"
  },
  {
    question: "The relativist view on confronting different systems of business ethics says that ___.",
    options: [
      "the same ethics should be practiced in other countries as at home",
      "ethical systems do not vary greatly between countries",
      "one should follow whatever practices are accepted in a certain place",
      "no one knows what the ethically correct way of doing business is"
    ],
    correctOption: "one should follow whatever practices are accepted in a certain place",
    difficulty: "beginner"
  },
  {
    question: "The absolutist view on confronting different systems of business ethics ignores the fact that ___.",
    options: [
      "people may disagree over the correct ethical standards",
      "ethical standards come from cultural views current in a location",
      "ethical standards in other countries may not be the same as those one is used to",
      "one may have to lower one’s standards in order to business effectively"
    ],
    correctOption: "ethical standards in other countries may not be the same as those one is used to",
    difficulty: "beginner"
  },
  {
    question: "The absolutist position on morality places the responsibility for setting standards on ___.",
    options: [
      "the local people where business is conducted",
      "the visitor to a foreign country",
      "the government of the country where business is conducted",
      "a single impartial and ethically ideal observer"
    ],
    correctOption: "a single impartial and ethically ideal observer",
    difficulty: "beginner"
  },
  {
    question: "The practice of respecting basic rights in international transactions ensures that ___.",
    options: [
      "a moral minimum will be respected",
      "no ethical transgressions will take place",
      "everyone will agree on all ethical standards",
      "everyone will understand each other culturally"
    ],
    correctOption: "a moral minimum will be respected",
    difficulty: "beginner"
  },
  {
    question: "One of Richard DeGeorge’s guidelines for multinational corporations is that ___.",
    options: [
      "they should carry out actions that benefit their home country",
      "they should conform to the ethical expectations of the local culture",
      "they should pay their employees the same as they pay their domestic employees",
      "they should do more good than harm for the host country"
    ],
    correctOption: "they should do more good than harm for the host country",
    difficulty: "beginner"
  },
  {
    question: "Justice must be strongly considered in international operations mainly because ___.",
    options: [
      "multinational corporations often are not familiar with local laws",
      "foreign investment most often benefits the rich rather than the poor",
      "globalized businesses tend to make more profits than other companies do",
      "multinational corporations have a duty to aid developing countries"
    ],
    correctOption: "foreign investment most often benefits the rich rather than the poor",
    difficulty: "beginner"
  },
  {
    question: "An internationally agreed-upon code of ethics includes an emphasis on ___.",
    options: [
      "profitability",
      "human rights",
      "politics",
      "abiding by the law"
    ],
    correctOption: "human rights",
    difficulty: "beginner"
  },
  {
    question: "Wage standards in developing countries are often very low mainly because ___.",
    options: [
      "wages are not set by the market",
      "developing countries do not have as many factories",
      "local politics prevents workers from campaigning for higher wages",
      "workers are willing to work for much less than someone comparable in the United States"
    ],
    correctOption: "workers are willing to work for much less than someone comparable in the United States",
    difficulty: "beginner"
  },
  {
    question: "ABC Corporation is an American company that wishes to do business with Rimonter, a corporation located in Asia. Rimonter has the standard practice of requiring an undocumented payment of $50,000 to a charitable organization headed by Rimonter's CEO. This payment is required in exchange for securing a manufacturing contract with Rimonter Corporation. In response to Rimonter's demand, ABC Corporation should ________.",
    options: [
      "agree to pay the $50,000 to the charitable organization but document the payment",
      "refuse to pay $50,000 to the charitable organization but offer to pay $10,000 instead",
      "refuse to pay $50,000 to the charitable organization and look for a different business partner",
      "agree to pay the $50,000 to the charitable organization in installments of $10,000 over the next 5 years"
    ],
    correctOption: "refuse to pay $50,000 to the charitable organization and look for a different business partner",
    difficulty: "beginner"
  },
  {
    question: "Shareholders have governance over a company in return for ___.",
    options: [
      "influence",
      "capital",
      "prestige",
      "advertising"
    ],
    correctOption: "capital",
    difficulty: "beginner"
  },
  {
    question: "The property rights theory of corporations has it that incorporation ___.",
    options: [
      "is a general aspect of ownership",
      "is a matter of owning enough capital",
      "should be accompanied by rules",
      "is anyone’s right"
    ],
    correctOption: "should be accompanied by rules",
    difficulty: "beginner"
  },
  {
    question: "Although Electronics, Inc. has a code of ethics for its subcontractors, it has experienced issues with its government contracts. Several subcontractors have been embroiled in scandals involving unethical conduct. Most recently, a subcontractor falsified thousands of dollars in work orders. If Electronics, Inc. wants to show the government that it is serious about preventing unethical conduct, it should ________.",
    options: [
      "educate subcontractors about its expectations and monitor them for compliance",
      "emphasize that it bears little responsibility for the subcontractor's behavior because the subcontractor is not an employee by law",
      "warn subcontractors about the perils of getting caught",
      "provide proof of its code of ethics which prohibits unethical conduct"
    ],
    correctOption: "educate subcontractors about its expectations and monitor them for compliance",
    difficulty: "beginner"
  },
  {
    question: "Accountants, Inc. wishes to expand its accounting practice to include both consulting and auditing services. Which aspect of its strategy should be examined more closely?",
    options: [
      "The accounting firm has failed to take into account that auditing is more lucrative than consulting.",
      "Hiring an accounting firm for consultation can be problematic because it is not a widely accepted business practice.",
      "CPAs are not qualified to give advice beyond accounting and financial matters.",
      "Conflicts of interest are likely to arise from offering both services to one client."
    ],
    correctOption: "Conflicts of interest are likely to arise from offering both services to one client.",
    difficulty: "beginner"
  },
  {
    question: "Adolf Berle argued against public responsibility of a corporation on the basis of ___.",
    options: [
      "the rights of stakeholders",
      "limiting the power of shareholders",
      "excessive managerial power",
      "corporations’ impact on society"
    ],
    correctOption: "excessive managerial power",
    difficulty: "beginner"
  },
  {
    question: "Although ABC Corporation has a comprehensive ethics program, several of its employees have been charged with financial fraud. If ABC is subsequently convicted of the crime and sentenced under the Federal Sentencing Guidelines, it can expect ________.",
    options: [
      "strict sanctions without the possibility of leniency",
      "lenient sanctions because it has a comprehensive ethics program",
      "standard sanctions regardless of its comprehensive ethics program",
      "reassurance of no sanctions because it has a comprehensive ethics program"
    ],
    correctOption: "lenient sanctions because it has a comprehensive ethics program",
    difficulty: "beginner"
  },
  {
    question: "The central argument for shareholder control of a company states that ___.",
    options: [
      "companies without shareholders are not likely to be profitable",
      "shareholders have the most to lose in their company involvement",
      "shareholders are more likely than management to operate a company profitably",
      "management can only control a company insofar as they are paid by it"
    ],
    correctOption: "shareholders have the most to lose in their company involvement",
    difficulty: "beginner"
  },
  {
    question: "According to stakeholder theory, ___ .",
    options: [
      "stakeholders invest the most capital in a corporation",
      "a company ought to be run to the benefit of everyone involved in it",
      "everyone involved in a company should be treated as shareholders",
      "ownership of a company should be divided among all stakeholders"
    ],
    correctOption: "a company ought to be run to the benefit of everyone involved in it",
    difficulty: "beginner"
  },
  {
    question: "Unethical business conduct usually arises from ___.",
    options: [
      "ignorance of the law",
      "unscrupulous individuals acting alone",
      "attempts to cheat shareholders of their dividends",
      "the way that an organization as a whole operates"
    ],
    correctOption: "the way that an organization as a whole operates",
    difficulty: "beginner"
  },
  {
    question: "An effective corporate ethics program should include ___.",
    options: [
      "standards that have been communicated to all levels",
      "oversight given to a few individuals",
      "training in all of the relevant laws",
      "reporting of all procedures to the public"
    ],
    correctOption: "standards that have been communicated to all levels",
    difficulty: "beginner"
  },
  {
    question: "Which of the following arguments are used by those organizations that support the goal of diversity in the workforce?",
    options: [
      "Affirmative action plans eliminate reverse discrimination.",
      "Global marketplaces can only be developed with exposure to diversity.",
      "Racial discrimination still exists today and must be ended.",
      "Sexism and racist bigotry deny women and minorities opportunities."
    ],
    correctOption: "Global marketplaces can only be developed with exposure to diversity.",
    difficulty: "beginner"
  },
  {
    question: "Which of the following must be involved in order to have discrimination in employment?",
    options: [
      "The discrimination must be based on long-standing beliefs about a person or group.",
      "The decision must be based on prejudice.",
      "The decision must be based on individual merit.",
      "The decision must be supported by the institution or organization."
    ],
    correctOption: "The decision must be supported by the institution or organization.",
    difficulty: "beginner"
  },
  {
    question: "Decisions based on _____ are decisions based on ideas about race, gender, or other stereotypes.",
    options: [
      "a negative impact",
      "a harmful impact",
      "individual merit",
      "prejudice"
    ],
    correctOption: "prejudice",
    difficulty: "beginner"
  },
  {
    question: "Which of the following is carried out as the result of unconscious factors such as processes that have unintended outcomes?",
    options: [
      "Intentional discrimination",
      "Unintentional discrimination",
      "Individual discrimination",
      "Institutional discrimination"
    ],
    correctOption: "Unintentional discrimination",
    difficulty: "beginner"
  },
  {
    question: "Which of the following types of discrimination has widespread effects within an organization because it is based on processes and policies?",
    options: [
      "Intentional",
      "Unintentional",
      "Individual",
      "Institutional"
    ],
    correctOption: "Institutional",
    difficulty: "beginner"
  },
  {
    question: "Which of the following forms of discrimination is the result of one or a few people acting on their own?",
    options: [
      "Intentional",
      "Unintentional",
      "Individual",
      "Institutional"
    ],
    correctOption: "Individual",
    difficulty: "beginner"
  },
  {
    question: "Which of the following viewed discrimination as an intentional act by an organization and sought to eliminate discrimination on the part of the employer?",
    options: [
      "Executive Order 11246",
      "Affirmative action",
      "Equal Employment Opportunity Act of 1972",
      "Title VII of the Civil Rights Act of 1964"
    ],
    correctOption: "Title VII of the Civil Rights Act of 1964",
    difficulty: "beginner"
  },
  {
    question: "Which of the following describes an indication that discrimination exists because there is a disproportionate number of a protected group in less desirable positions within the organization?",
    options: [
      "Prima facie",
      "Intentionality",
      "Adverse impact",
      "Affirmative action"
    ],
    correctOption: "Adverse impact",
    difficulty: "beginner"
  },
  {
    question: "Families headed by single women are now _____ as likely to be poor compared to families headed by single men.",
    options: [
      "twice",
      "three times",
      "four times",
      "five times"
    ],
    correctOption: "five times",
    difficulty: "beginner"
  },
  {
    question: "Which of the following describes the relationship between pay and the number of women working in an occupation?",
    options: [
      "The more women in an occupation, the higher the pay for that occupation.",
      "The more women in an occupation, the lower the pay for that occupation.",
      "The fewer women in an occupation, the higher the pay for women in that occupation.",
      "The fewer women in an occupation, the lower the pay for everyone in that occupation."
    ],
    correctOption: "The more women in an occupation, the lower the pay for that occupation.",
    difficulty: "beginner"
  },
  {
    question: "Which of the following is considered to be the most fundamental elements of a rational organization?",
    options: [
      "Top managers",
      "Organizational charts",
      "Formal hierarchies of authority",
      "Operations"
    ],
    correctOption: "Formal hierarchies of authority",
    difficulty: "beginner"
  },
  {
    question: "Who directly produces the goods and services that are the essential outputs of an organization?",
    options: [
      "Agents",
      "Middle managers",
      "Consumers",
      "Operating layer employees"
    ],
    correctOption: "Operating layer employees",
    difficulty: "beginner"
  },
  {
    question: "Which of the following indicates an employee’s moral responsibility to obey the employer and the employer’s moral responsibility to provide wages and working conditions it agreed to provide?",
    options: [
      "Contractual agreements",
      "Rational agreements",
      "Moral obligations",
      "Rational obligations"
    ],
    correctOption: "Moral obligations",
    difficulty: "beginner"
  },
  {
    question: "Which of the following is a type of conflict of interest based on emotional ties and relationships?",
    options: [
      "Actual",
      "Subjective",
      "Apparent",
      "Objective"
    ],
    correctOption: "Subjective",
    difficulty: "beginner"
  },
  {
    question: "Which of the following exists when there is no conflict of interest, but other people who consider the employee’s situation believe that the employee has a conflict of interest?",
    options: [
      "Actual",
      "Subjective",
      "Apparent",
      "Ethical"
    ],
    correctOption: "Apparent",
    difficulty: "beginner"
  },
  {
    question: "Which of the following is an example of commercial extortion?",
    options: [
      "Something of value is offered to an employee if the employee deals favorably with the firm.",
      "Payment, preferential treatment, or goods are offered when an employee shows preference to an organization.",
      "An employee uses the resources of the employer for his or her own benefit without the consent of the employer.",
      "An employee demands a payment of money or goods from an organization in order to continue doing business together."
    ],
    correctOption: "An employee demands a payment of money or goods from an organization in order to continue doing business together.",
    difficulty: "beginner"
  },
  {
    question: "Which of the following is proprietary information that concerns a company’s activities, technologies, plans, policies, and other information that, if known to competitors, could affect the company’s ability to compete?",
    options: [
      "Trade secrets",
      "Commercial extortion",
      "Conflict of interest",
      "Insider trading"
    ],
    correctOption: "Trade secrets",
    difficulty: "beginner"
  },
  {
    question: "Which of the following describes an organization model that focuses less on formal lines of authority and communication, and more on the lines of competing power coalitions and lines of influence and communication that stem from these coalitions?",
    options: [
      "Rational",
      "Political",
      "Justice-based",
      "Goal-directed"
    ],
    correctOption: "Political",
    difficulty: "beginner"
  },
  {
    question: "Which of the following represents the three basic differences between the power of corporate managers and the power of government officials?",
    options: [
      "Centralization, decision-making process, and legal authority",
      "Economic leverage, mobility, and decentralization",
      "Consent, limits, and mobility",
      "Monopoly power, legal authority, and consent"
    ],
    correctOption: "Consent, limits, and mobility",
    difficulty: "beginner"
  },
  {
    question: "The right of people to determine what, to whom, and how much information they disclose to others is called",
    options: [
      "psychological privacy.",
      "physical privacy.",
      "the technological dilemma of modern organizations.",
      "the right to privacy."
    ],
    correctOption: "the right to privacy.",
    difficulty: "beginner"
  },
  {
    question: "From which external environment does a corporation draw the raw materials needed for a finished product?",
    options: [
      "Consumer",
      "Natural",
      "Competition",
      "Social"
    ],
    correctOption: "Natural",
    difficulty: "intermediate"
  },
  {
    question: "According to Michael Renner from the Worldwatch Institute’s State of the World 2015 report, what is driving most of our environmental problems?",
    options: [
      "Economic growth",
      "Landfill growth",
      "Income growth",
      "Technology growth"
    ],
    correctOption: "Economic growth",
    difficulty: "intermediate"
  },
  {
    question: "Which of the following describes the undesirable contamination of the environment by human activities?",
    options: [
      "Resource depletion",
      "Greenhouse effect",
      "Pollution",
      "Global warming"
    ],
    correctOption: "Pollution",
    difficulty: "intermediate"
  },
  {
    question: "Which of the following absorbs and holds heat from the sun, thereby contributing to the heating of the atmosphere?",
    options: [
      "Global warming",
      "Acid rain",
      "Chlorofluorocarbons",
      "Greenhouse gases"
    ],
    correctOption: "Greenhouse gases",
    difficulty: "intermediate"
  },
  {
    question: "Which of the following is considered to be one of the most prevalent sources of the six most common forms of air pollution, affecting the air we breathe, human health, and the environment, and creating property damage?",
    options: [
      "Airborne toxins produced by carcinogens such as cigarette smoke",
      "Acid rain produced by burning sulfur from resources such as coal",
      "Chlorofluorocarbons produced by items such as refrigerators and air conditioners",
      "Gases and particulates produced by automobiles"
    ],
    correctOption: "Gases and particulates produced by automobiles",
    difficulty: "intermediate"
  },
  {
    question: "Which of the following is the main source of greenhouse gas emissions?",
    options: [
      "Power generation",
      "Farming",
      "Oil drilling and processing",
      "Industrial processes"
    ],
    correctOption: "Power generation",
    difficulty: "intermediate"
  },
  {
    question: "Which of the following describes the belief that concern for nature should be based on how the environment affects the interests of human beings?",
    options: [
      "Ecological ethics",
      "Utilitarianism",
      "Teleological center of life",
      "Anthropocentric views"
    ],
    correctOption: "Anthropocentric views",
    difficulty: "intermediate"
  },
  {
    question: "Which of the following describes the view that we have a moral obligation to protect nonhuman parts of the environment simply because they deserve to be protected?",
    options: [
      "Anthropocentric values",
      "Ecological ethics",
      "Absolute bans",
      "Teleological ethics"
    ],
    correctOption: "Ecological ethics",
    difficulty: "intermediate"
  },
  {
    question: "Who claimed that a livable environment is not just something we would like to have, rather, it is something others have a duty to allow us to have?",
    options: [
      "Paul Taylor",
      "Albert Schweitzer",
      "William Blackstone",
      "Aldo Leopold"
    ],
    correctOption: "William Blackstone",
    difficulty: "intermediate"
  },
  {
    question: "Which of the following describes the external price that must be paid by those in surrounding communities when pollutants are generated?",
    options: [
      "Private costs",
      "Divergent costs",
      "Market costs",
      "Social costs"
    ],
    correctOption: "Social costs",
    difficulty: "intermediate"
  },
  {
    question: "Which of the following is one of the advantages of ethical decision-making as a long-term business strategy?",
    options: [
      "Ethical behavior will increase short-term profits.",
      "Ethical behavior will provide positive press opportunities.",
      "Ethical behavior can ensure positive employee relationships.",
      "Ethical behavior can provide significant competitive advantage."
    ],
    correctOption: "Ethical behavior can provide significant competitive advantage.",
    difficulty: "intermediate"
  },
  {
    question: "Which of the following is defined as standards of what a group or individual feels is right or wrong, or good or evil?",
    options: [
      "Morality",
      "Ethics",
      "Standards",
      "Values"
    ],
    correctOption: "Morality",
    difficulty: "intermediate"
  },
  {
    question: "Which of the following best describes the criteria by which we judge manners and rules of behavior?",
    options: [
      "Ethical norms",
      "Moral norms",
      "Nonmoral standards",
      "Standard values"
    ],
    correctOption: "Nonmoral standards",
    difficulty: "intermediate"
  },
  {
    question: "Which of the following can be described as an example of a moral standard?",
    options: [
      "Do not be late for a meeting.",
      "Do not harm others.",
      "Do not use a work computer for personal use.",
      "Do not discuss pay issues with others."
    ],
    correctOption: "Do not harm others.",
    difficulty: "intermediate"
  },
  {
    question: "Which of the following best describes the basis for moral standards?",
    options: [
      "Moral standards are based on authority.",
      "Moral standards deal with serious issues.",
      "Moral standards are based on personal experiences.",
      "Moral standards are based on personal beliefs."
    ],
    correctOption: "Moral standards deal with serious issues.",
    difficulty: "intermediate"
  },
  {
    question: "Which of the following best describes ethical standards?",
    options: [
      "Norms of behavior in a society",
      "Laws that govern acceptable behavior",
      "How reasonable moral standards are when applied to your life",
      "Universal standards based on impartial rules"
    ],
    correctOption: "How reasonable moral standards are when applied to your life",
    difficulty: "intermediate"
  },
  {
    question: "Ethical issues about the economic, political, or legal aspects that a business operates under are referred to as _____ issues.",
    options: [
      "corporate",
      "individual",
      "governmental",
      "systemic"
    ],
    correctOption: "systemic",
    difficulty: "intermediate"
  },
  {
    question: "Because companies intentionally engage in actions such as production and sales, some people believe they should be held morally responsible for their decisions and actions. This view considers companies as having to act as",
    options: [
      "moral agents.",
      "machines.",
      "individuals.",
      "regulators."
    ],
    correctOption: "moral agents.",
    difficulty: "intermediate"
  },
  {
    question: "There have been several arguments against business ethics. Which argument best supports the idea that when an organization makes money, it improves society, so business ethics are not needed?",
    options: [
      "If it’s legal, it is ethical.",
      "Profits benefit all.",
      "The Loyal Agent states it.",
      "Conflict is not unusual."
    ],
    correctOption: "Profits benefit all.",
    difficulty: "intermediate"
  },
  {
    question: "Which of the following best describes an organization’s obligations toward society?",
    options: [
      "Ethics",
      "Morals",
      "Values",
      "Corporate social responsibility"
    ],
    correctOption: "Corporate social responsibility",
    difficulty: "intermediate"
  },
  {
    "question": "What do counselors in high school settings primarily emphasize?",
    "options": [
        "career development and academic advisement",
        "pet therapy",
        "psychotherapy",
        "bibliotherapy"
    ],
    "correctOption": "career development and academic advisement",
    "difficulty": "advanced"
},
{
    "question": "In which educational setting do counselors pay close attention to variations in physical development and issues related to self-image and sexual development?",
    "options": [
        "elementary setting",
        "middle school setting",
        "high school setting",
        "college setting"
    ],
    "correctOption": "middle school setting",
    "difficulty": "advanced"
},
{
    "question": "Counselors focusing primarily on preventive measures would likely specialize in which setting?",
    "options": [
        "college settings",
        "high school settings",
        "middle school settings",
        "elementary settings"
    ],
    "correctOption": "elementary settings",
    "difficulty": "advanced"
},
{
    "question": "What educational initiative created an emphasis on socially and economically disadvantaged students to close the achievement gap?",
    "options": [
        "The ASCA National Model",
        "No Child Left Behind Act (NCLB) of 2001",
        "World War II",
        "All of the above"
    ],
    "correctOption": "No Child Left Behind Act (NCLB) of 2001",
    "difficulty": "advanced"
},
{
    "question": "Which theory is NOT considered a major career counseling theory?",
    "options": [
        "developmental",
        "trait and factor",
        "social cognitive",
        "Gestalt"
    ],
    "correctOption": "Gestalt",
    "difficulty": "advanced"
},
{
    "question": "Which theorist is best characterized as a developmental career theorist?",
    "options": [
        "Super",
        "Holland",
        "Roe",
        "Parsons"
    ],
    "correctOption": "Super",
    "difficulty": "advanced"
},
{
    "question": "Which stage is NOT included in Super's theory of career development?",
    "options": [
        "growth",
        "establishment",
        "tenure",
        "decline"
    ],
    "correctOption": "tenure",
    "difficulty": "advanced"
},
{
    "question": "Which career theory is considered most appropriate for multicultural clients due to its emphasis on environmental and social factors?",
    "options": [
        "Developmental career theory",
        "Social cognitive career theory",
        "Psychodynamic career theory",
        "Trait and factor theory"
    ],
    "correctOption": "Social cognitive career theory",
    "difficulty": "advanced"
},
{
    "question": "Which is NOT a basic stage of the trait and factor theory?",
    "options": [
        "A knowledge of the requirements and conditions of success, advantages, and disadvantages, compensations, opportunities, and prospects in different lines of work",
        "Clear understanding of aptitudes, abilities, interests, ambitions, resources, limitations, and their causes",
        "The ability to reason on the above two groups of facts",
        "All of the above are stages of the trait and factor theory"
    ],
    "correctOption": "All of the above are stages of the trait and factor theory",
    "difficulty": "advanced"
},
{
    "question": "What is true about social cognitive career theory (SCCT)?",
    "options": [
        "has its roots in social learning theory",
        "explores irrational thoughts about one's career",
        "using cognitions as motivation for career change",
        "All of the above"
    ],
    "correctOption": "has its roots in social learning theory",
    "difficulty": "advanced"
},
{
    "question": "Which of the following is NOT a source of occupational information?",
    "options": [
        "the Occupational Outlook Handbook (OOH)",
        "SIGI-PLUS",
        "Occupational Information Network (O*NET)",
        "the Dictionary of Careers"
    ],
    "correctOption": "the Dictionary of Careers",
    "difficulty": "advanced"
},
{
    "question": "What term describes something that provides satisfaction but may not provide any monetary gain?",
    "options": [
        "career",
        "avocation",
        "job",
        "occupation"
    ],
    "correctOption": "avocation",
    "difficulty": "advanced"
},
{
    "question": "Which career theory can be traced back to Frank Parsons?",
    "options": [
        "trait-factor",
        "psychodynamic",
        "developmental",
        "social cognitive"
    ],
    "correctOption": "trait-factor",
    "difficulty": "advanced"
},
{
    "question": "Which statement correctly pairs theorists with their corresponding career theories?",
    "options": [
        "social learning theory of career decision making; developmental theory",
        "developmental theory; social learning theory of career decision making",
        "trait and factor theory; developmental theory",
        "developmental theory; trait and factor theory"
    ],
    "correctOption": "developmental theory; social learning theory of career decision making",
    "difficulty": "advanced"
},
{
    "question": "In the early 1900's, where did counselors primarily help clients find employment?",
    "options": [
        "hospitals",
        "private practice",
        "prisons",
        "schools"
    ],
    "correctOption": "schools",
    "difficulty": "advanced"
},
{
    "question": "What helped propel the role of the professional school counselor into a new era by the end of the 20th century?",
    "options": [
        "The comprehensive developmental counseling curriculum",
        "The creation of national standards for school counseling programs",
        "Both of the above",
        "None of the above"
    ],
    "correctOption": "Both of the above",
    "difficulty": "advanced"
},
{
    "question": "What did ASCA replace the national standards with in 2014?",
    "options": [
        "new professional competencies for the elementary, middle, and high school levels",
        "Mindsets and Behaviors for Student Success",
        "a renewed focus on career development standards across all grade levels",
        "All of the above"
    ],
    "correctOption": "Mindsets and Behaviors for Student Success",
    "difficulty": "advanced"
},
{
    "question": "Which type of counselors typically maintain a primary emphasis on developmental issues and prevention strategies?",
    "options": [
        "Elementary school counselors",
        "Middle school counselors",
        "High school counselors",
        "Private practice counselors"
    ],
    "correctOption": "Elementary school counselors",
    "difficulty": "advanced"
},
{
    "question": "Which counselors are sensitive to students creating a sense of identity while emphasizing academic advising, educational planning, and career development?",
    "options": [
        "Elementary school counselors",
        "Middle school counselors",
        "High school counselors",
        "College counselors"
    ],
    "correctOption": "High school counselors",
    "difficulty": "advanced"
},
{
    "question": "Which counselors typically focus on transitions and topics such as decision-making, conflict resolution, peer pressures, and sexuality?",
    "options": [
        "Elementary school counselors",
        "Middle school counselors",
        "High school counselors",
        "College counselors"
    ],
    "correctOption": "Middle school counselors",
    "difficulty": "advanced"
},
{
    "question": "What was created in response to the No Child Left Behind Act (NCLB) of 2001?",
    "options": [
        "Mindsets and Behaviors for Student Success",
        "The ASCA National Model: A Framework for School Counseling Programs",
        "Both of the above",
        "None of the above"
    ],
    "correctOption": "The ASCA National Model: A Framework for School Counseling Programs",
    "difficulty": "advanced"
}
];